<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-10-25T13:11:48-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Dad Notes</title><subtitle>These are notes I'm leaving for the adults that my children will become
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Dealing with Loss</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/25/dealing-with-loss.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dealing with Loss" /><published>2017-10-25T08:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-10-25T08:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/25/dealing-with-loss</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/25/dealing-with-loss.html">&lt;p&gt;You’re going to lose something or someone important to you. It will hurt in ways you don’t understand, and the hurt will live inside emotions that don’t make sense. You’ll feel angry, sorrow, regret, shame, misery, emptiness, hopelessness and even sometimes joy. The most important thing is to identify that you’re feeling the loss. Sometimes it’s easy because it’s a friend or colleague or relative you lose. Other times it won’t be as easy to understand the source of the grief, especially when you lose a &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt; or a disproved idea you’ve long held as true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you struggle with loss, you need to understand that it’s okay. If you fight the feelings, they will linger like an unwanted houseguest and mess up other parts of your life until you accept and address them. Live in the moment of the pain, accept that it’s real, and lean on your faith and your friends to help you through the parts you can’t manage alone. It’s a gift to your friends to allow them to help you, and you’ll need the help anyway. Win-win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One final note: you will lose something important to you no matter how hard you try to avoid it. Don’t try to avoid the pain of loss by avoiding meaningful relationships and dreams.  You need those. Without them your heart will grow cold and hard and you’ll end up far worse by withdrawing than you would in dealing with the pain of loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love freely. Accept the loss that comes as part of the deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love, &lt;br /&gt;
Dad&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">You’re going to lose something or someone important to you. It will hurt in ways you don’t understand, and the hurt will live inside emotions that don’t make sense. You’ll feel angry, sorrow, regret, shame, misery, emptiness, hopelessness and even sometimes joy. The most important thing is to identify that you’re feeling the loss. Sometimes it’s easy because it’s a friend or colleague or relative you lose. Other times it won’t be as easy to understand the source of the grief, especially when you lose a thing or a disproved idea you’ve long held as true.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Get Messy, Get Simple</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/14/get-messy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Get Messy, Get Simple" /><published>2017-06-14T08:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-06-14T08:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/06/14/get-messy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/14/get-messy.html">&lt;p&gt;Life is messy. It’s full of trouble waiting for you to find it. Among other things, you’ll find yourself in relationships with manipulative people, you’ll encounter difficult financial problems that don’t have easy answers, and you’ll make decisions that lead to consequences no one could have foreseen. Each of your choices will lead to other choices. Everything builds on something in the past. Because of that, seek simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn how to take complex problems and break them down into pieces and tackle each smaller bit one at a time. Treat people fairly and seek out friends who do the same. When faced with multiple choices, choose the simplest thing that achieves your goal. Because just like when you mixed Play-Doh colors together as a kid, you’ll find that some things in life can’t be undone. Be purposeful about the small decisions and you won’t regret the big places that leads you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get messy with life. There’s no other choice sometimes, so you might as well get used to it. Then learn how to spot simplicity and choose it when you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love, &lt;br /&gt;
Dad&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Life is messy. It’s full of trouble waiting for you to find it. Among other things, you’ll find yourself in relationships with manipulative people, you’ll encounter difficult financial problems that don’t have easy answers, and you’ll make decisions that lead to consequences no one could have foreseen. Each of your choices will lead to other choices. Everything builds on something in the past. Because of that, seek simplicity.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dad is Weird</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/03/dad-is-weird.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dad is Weird" /><published>2017-06-03T23:26:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-06-03T23:26:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/06/03/dad-is-weird</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/03/dad-is-weird.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ve already started to pick up on this. You should know by the time you read this that your dad is… weird. I don’t do the same kinds of things as everyone else, and I don’t think like other people think. I generally take the hard way where there’s an easy one available if I think there’s something to be learned. I try to solve problems my way first and then I look at how other people solved the same problem. My ideas are rarely the best ones in comparison, but that’s not a problem to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do things on principle even when it would be possible to take a shortcut when no one would know the difference. I believe that character is built through adversity, so I welcome challenging times because of the growth they will cause. Sometimes I just dance or sing or act like a goof. (This is sure to provide entertainment and embarrassment to you.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m weird. I want you to be weird too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love, &lt;br /&gt;
Dad&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">You’ve already started to pick up on this. You should know by the time you read this that your dad is… weird. I don’t do the same kinds of things as everyone else, and I don’t think like other people think. I generally take the hard way where there’s an easy one available if I think there’s something to be learned. I try to solve problems my way first and then I look at how other people solved the same problem. My ideas are rarely the best ones in comparison, but that’s not a problem to me.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Be Brave</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/31/be-brave.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Be Brave" /><published>2017-05-31T08:56:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-31T08:56:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/31/be-brave</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/31/be-brave.html">&lt;p&gt;You’re going to reach a point in life where this hits home. If I can help it hit a little sooner, I’ll consider this note a success. One day, you will wake up and the burdens and fear will have piled up to a point that you’ll realize there’s no one around you that can pull you out. Not even me. It will scare you a lot. The fortress of support that you believed would hold forever will show cracks at the foundations. You may even be paralyzed by fear, and you won’t know how to get through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be the test of your reserve and your training. While I can’t pull you through, I can give you the tools and the hope you need to succeed. Because while there won’t be anyone around you who can help you, you’re not alone. You have a Creator who loves you and He’s even there in the worst case scenario. As soon as you learn to resign the burdens that you were never meant to carry, you will experience the freedom that needs no fortress to contain and protect it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go out, be brave, and explore who you were meant to be. You don’t need a safety net, you already have everything you need to find the work that fulfills you and the life you were meant to live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love, &lt;br /&gt;
Dad&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">You’re going to reach a point in life where this hits home. If I can help it hit a little sooner, I’ll consider this note a success. One day, you will wake up and the burdens and fear will have piled up to a point that you’ll realize there’s no one around you that can pull you out. Not even me. It will scare you a lot. The fortress of support that you believed would hold forever will show cracks at the foundations. You may even be paralyzed by fear, and you won’t know how to get through.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Here We Go</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/30/here-we-go.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Here We Go" /><published>2017-05-30T22:54:26-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-30T22:54:26-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/30/here-we-go</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/30/here-we-go.html">&lt;p&gt;First things first. I’ve been thinking about writing to your future selves for several years. I have several reasons for this, none of which are important right now. What is important is this: you matter to me. The amazing people that you grow up to be will be shaped in part by your mom and me, but we are raising you so that your unique personalities will be intact and shine through. So without further introduction, I want to drop some wisdom on you that took me too long to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In life, there will be people that you disagree with and who disagree with you. A lot of them. Probably most, but thankfully not all. They will be all around you, and when you encounter them you will have to make a choice for each and every one of them. You can choose to marginalize them in your mind, to write them off as unimportant because you don’t see eye to eye. (Sometimes you will have to let people go when they aren’t dealing with you sincerely.) You can also choose to fight against them bitterly and attempt to tear them down with arguments or harsh words or other destructive means. Or you can choose another way altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can choose to recognize their intrinsic worth. You can value them as humans. You can listen to their words, along with the things behind that they are not saying. You can be swayed by the merit of their arguments, or you can reject what they are saying. Somehow you can still love them and value them, and they might recognize it. If they do, your words will carry more weight. The “somehow” part isn’t magic, but we’ll get to that later. It’s important to recognize that their souls are just as valuable as yours and maybe more broken. Love them, and because you choose to love them also choose to empathize with them. Put your empathy to work: act in compassion. Be as kind in dealing with them as you are in dealing with your closest friends. It’s hard but not impossible. I hope that when you read this you will recognize how I have modeled this for you as an example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love, &lt;br /&gt;
Dad&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">First things first. I’ve been thinking about writing to your future selves for several years. I have several reasons for this, none of which are important right now. What is important is this: you matter to me. The amazing people that you grow up to be will be shaped in part by your mom and me, but we are raising you so that your unique personalities will be intact and shine through. So without further introduction, I want to drop some wisdom on you that took me too long to learn.</summary></entry></feed>